{
    "questions": [{
            "qId" : 1,
            "questionText": "Which of the following does TypeScript use to specify types?",
            "options": [
				{
					"_id":    1,
                    "text": ":",
                    "correct": true
                },
                {
					"_id":    2,
                    "text": ";"
                },
                {
					"_id":    3,
                    "text": "!"
                },
                {
					"_id":    4,
                    "text": "&"
                }
				
				
            ],
			"answer":   1,
            "explanation": "TS uses a colon (:) to separate the property name from the property type"
        },
        {
            "qId" : 2,
            "questionText": "Which of the following is NOT a type used in TypeScript?",
            "options": [
				{	"_id":    1,
                    "text": "number"
                },
                {
					"_id":    2,
                    "text": "string"
                },
                {
					"_id":    3,
                    "text": "boolean"
                },
                {
					"_id":    4,
                    "text": "enum",
                    "correct": true
                }
            ],
			"answer":   4,
            "explanation": "enum is not used as a type in TypeScript"
        },
        {
            "qId" : 3,
            "questionText": "How can we specify properties and methods for an object in TypeScript?",
            "options": [{
					"_id":    1,
                    "text": "Use classes."
                },
                {
					"_id":    2,
                    "text": "Use interfaces.",
                    "correct": true
                },
                {
					"_id":    3,
                    "text": "Use enums."
                },
                {
					"_id":    4,
                    "text": "Use async/await."
                }
            ],
			"answer":   2,
            "explanation": "interfaces are typically used to list the properties and methods for an object"
        },
        {
            "qId" : 4,
            "questionText": "How else can Array<number> be written in TypeScript?",
            "options": [{
					"_id":    1,
                    "text": "@number"
                },
                {
					"_id":    2,
                    "text": "number[]",
                    "correct": true
                },
                {
					"_id":    3,
                    "text": "number!"
                },
                {
					"_id":    4,
                    "text": "number?"
                }
            ],
			"answer":   2,
            "explanation": "number[] is another way of writing Array<number> in TypeScript"
        },
        {
            "qId" : 5,
            "questionText": "In which of these does a class take parameters?",
            "options": [{
					"_id":    1,
                    "text": "constructor",
                    "correct": true
                },
                {
					"_id":    2,
                    "text": "destructor"
                },
                {
					"_id":    3,
                    "text": "import"
                },
                {
					"_id":    4,
                    "text": "subscribe"
                }
            ],
			"answer":   1,
            "explanation": "a constructor is used by a class to take in parameters"
        },
        {
            "qId" : 6,
            "questionText": "Which is NOT an access modifier?",
            "options": [{
					"_id":    1,
                    "text": "private"
                },
                {
					"_id":    2,
                    "text": "protected"
                },
                {
					"_id":    3,
                    "text": "public"
                },
                {
					"_id":    4,
                    "text": "async",
                    "correct": true
                }
            ],
			"answer":   4,
            "explanation": "async is not used as an access modifier type in TypeScript"
        },
        {
            "qId" : 7,
            "questionText": "Which keyword allows us to share information between files in TypeScript?",
            "options": [{
					"_id":    1,
                    "text": "import"
                },
                {
					"_id":    2,
                    "text": "export",
                    "correct": true
                },
                {
					"_id":    3,
                    "text": "async"
                },
                {
					"_id":    4,
                    "text": "constructor"
                }
            ],
			"answer":   2,
            "explanation": "the export keyword allows for the information to be transmitted between files"
        },
        {
            "qId" : 8,
            "questionText": "Which is an array method to generate a new array based on a condition?",
            "options": [{
					"_id":    1,
                    "text": "filter",
                    "correct": true
                },
                {
					"_id":    2,
                    "text": "map"
                },
                {
					"_id":    3,
                    "text": "async"
                },
                {
					"_id":    4,
                    "text": "enum"
                }
            ],
			"answer":   1,
            "explanation": "filter is a method used to conditionally create a new array"
        },
        {
            "qId" : 9,
            "questionText": "How is a property accessible within a class?",
            "options": [{
					"_id":    1,
                    "text": "Using this.propertyName",
                    "correct": true
                },
                {
					"_id":    2,
                    "text": "Accessors"
                },
                {
					"_id":    3,
                    "text": "Destructuring"
                },
                {
					"_id":    4,
                    "text": "Arrow function"
                }
            ],
			"answer":   1,
            "explanation": "this.propertyName is the way to access a specific property within a class"
        },
        {
            "qId" : 10,
            "questionText": "Duplicate: is a property accessible within a class?",
            "options": [{
					"_id":    1,
                    "text": "Using this.propertyName",
                    "correct": true
                },
                {
					"_id":    2,
                    "text": "Accessors"
                },
                {
					"_id":    3,
                    "text": "Destructuring"
                },
                {
					"_id":    4,
                    "text": "Arrow function"
                }
            ],
			"answer":   1,
            "explanation": "this.propertyName is the way to access a specific property within a class"
        }

    ]
}